本期视频由Audible赞助
This episode of Primal Space is supported by Audible,
前往下方链接获取首季度半价资格
get 3 months for half price by visiting Audible.com/primalspace
1989年 哈勃太空望远镜发射升空
When the Hubble Telescope launched in 1989,
它将用它拍摄的每一张照片来拓展我们对宇宙的理解
it promised to expand our understanding of the universe with every picture it took.
在三十年的服役期内 它的确做到了
After 30 years of service, it did exactly that.
从对遥远星系 恒星的观测 到对宇宙年龄的准确测算
From observing distant stars and galaxies, to measuring the exact age of our universe,
哈勃解开了如此多的未解之谜
Hubble answered so many questions.
是时候解决下一阶段的问题 进一步探寻宇宙的奥秘了
Now it's time to answer the next set of questions as we continue to uncover the mysteries of our universe.
本期视频我们将了解詹姆斯·韦伯太空望远镜
In this video, we're going to look at the James Webb Space Telescope.
我们还将了解它将观测什么
We're also going to look at what it will observe
以及它如何寻找最像地球 最可能有生命存在的星球
and how it could find the most Earth-like planets, with the highest chance of supporting life.
在轨30年 拍摄了数百万张照片后
After 30 years and millions of pictures later,
哈勃已经达到了它能观测到的最远宇宙的极限
the Hubble Telescope has peaked in terms of how far back into the universe it can observe.
哈勃最远的观测是于2016年拍摄的GNZ11星系
Hubble's furthest observation was made in 2016, when it captured an image of Galaxy GNZ11.
该星系位于320亿光年外
This Galaxy is 32 billion light-years away
但因宇宙的膨胀 它的光是134亿年前发出的
but due to the expansion of space, the light we see from it shows the Galaxy as it was 13.4 billion years ago.
虽然这是大爆炸后仅四百万年后
Although this is just 400 million years after the Big Bang,
哈勃却因其可观测的波长范围有限 再也无法看到更远的东西了
Hubble is unable to see anything further than this since it's limited by the range of wavelengths it can observe.
因为来自遥远星系的光在传播过程中
As the light from distant galaxies travels from one point to another,
它的波长会因宇宙的持续膨胀而被拉伸
its wavelength is stretched by the constant expansion of space.
当光到达哈勃的时候 它的波长会被拉伸到哈勃的可观测波长范围外
By the time the light reaches Hubble, it's stretched to a wavelength outside of Hubble's viewing range.
任何波长被拉伸到超过近红外波段的光都无法被哈勃观测到
Anything that's stretched to a wavelength above near infrared is unobservable by Hubble.
为了观测到宇宙中最遥远 最早期的物体
In order to observe the most distant and earliest objects in our universe,
我们需要在红外波段观察它们发出的光
we need to observe the infrared light that comes from them.
于是詹姆斯·韦伯太空望远镜诞生了
This is where the James Webb Telescope comes in.
在1996年 它的研发开始的时候
When development began in 1996,
许多望远镜需求的科技树还未被点亮
many of the technologies needed for the telescope had yet to be invented.
望远镜需要一个超大的太阳伞来保持自身的超低温度
An enormous sunshield is required to keep the telescope at an extremely low temperature.
还要为望远镜研发能够在超低温下正常运转的特定波段传感器
Special wavelength sensors that can operate at cryogenic temperatures
also had to be developed for this telescope.
韦伯将主要观测红外波段
James Webb will observe primarily in the infrared range,
能够看到哈勃无法观测的东西
which will allow it to see things that Hubble couldn't see.
当恒星与行星最初形成的时候
When stars and planets are first forming,
通常会被巨大的尘埃云挡住 吸收掉可见光
they're often hidden behind enormous clouds of dust which absorb visible light.
哈勃可以观测这些巨大的尘埃云 但无法看到它们背后有什么
Hubble is able to observe these magnificent clouds but it can't see what's going on behind them.
这是哈勃在2014年拍摄的著名的“创造之柱”
This is the famous Pillars of Creation Nebula which Hubble imaged in 2014.
以红外波段观测它则能清楚看到这些尘埃云背后发生了什么
Observing it in infrared light reveals just how much is going on behind these dusty clouds.
但韦伯并不是第一个红外波段太空望远镜
But James Webb won't be the first infrared space telescope.
多年来 太空中有过几个红外波段的望远镜
Over the years, there have been several infrared telescopes in space,
但没有哪个能达到韦伯那种细节和能力
but none of them have had the detail and capability that James Webb will have.
望远镜的分辨率由它的镜面能收集到的波长数量有关
The resolution of a telescope is limited by the number of wavelengths it can fit across its mirror.
更大的镜面就有更高的分辨率
A larger mirror allows for a higher resolution.
斯皮策红外望远镜的镜面直径只有0.85米
The Spitzer Infrared Telescope has a mirror just 0.85m in diameter.
哈勃的镜面略大于2.4米 而韦伯则有巨大的6.5米主镜
Hubble's mirror is slightly larger at 2.4m, but James Webb will have an enormous mirror, measuring 6.5m wide.
这将给望远镜带来无与伦比的分辨率
This will give the telescope an incredibly precise resolution,
可以从40公里外看到一枚硬币
capable of observing a penny from 40km away.
如果想观测宇宙中最遥远的星系与行星 这样的精度是必需的
This level of precision will be required
if it wants to discover the most distant galaxies and planets in our universe.
韦伯望远镜最让人拍案叫绝的目标
One of the most impressive goals of the James Webb Telescope
是寻找并分析遥远宇宙中像地球的行星
is to find and analyze the most distant Earth-like planets in our universe.
方法是让韦伯对焦在一个有已知行星围绕的恒星上
To do this, James Webb will focus on a single star which is known to have planets orbiting it.
当行星从前面公转过去时 望远镜会检测到亮度的轻微下降
As a planet crosses in front of the star, the telescope will measure a small dip in light.
这首先会帮助我们测算出行星的大小
At first, this will help to determine the size of the planet,
而从不同波长下观测亮度的下降程度则能给我们更多信息
but measuring dips in multiple wavelengths will give us even more information.
因为原子和分子会吸收不同波段的光
Since atoms and molecules absorb light at different wavelengths,
以某种特定波长的光测量变暗程度可以反映出行星大气存在哪种分子
measuring dips at specific wavelengths will signify which molecules are present in the planet's atmosphere.
如果望远镜检测到在1.15和1.4微米波长有衰减
If the telescope measures a dip in light at around 1.15 and 1.4 micrometres,
那我们就能知道该行星大气中存在水蒸气
we can tell that the planet's atmosphere contains water vapour,
因为水分子会大量吸收这两个波段的光
since H2O absorbs a larger amount of light at those wavelengths.
韦伯将能观测很大范围波长的光 从可见光到中红外波段
James Webb will be able to observe a large range of wavelengths from visible light through to mid infrared.
这对于观测地球上的几种常见分子是很有用的
This will be perfect for detecting various kinds of molecules that are common on Earth
比如二氧化碳 氧气和氮气
like: CO2, Oxygen and Nitrogen.
除了韦伯超高的精度
Along with Webb's incredible sensitivity,
还将在茫茫宇宙中寻找和我们最像的行星
it will be able to discover extremely distant planets that bear an uncanny resemblance to our own.
寻找那些和地球很像的行星可以让我们更好的了解我们自己的星球
Finding these Earth-like planets will teach us more about our own planet
还能进一步尝试证明我们在浩渺星辰中并不是孤独的
while taking us one step closer to proving that we are not alone in this vast cosmic arena.
当我们耐心等待詹姆斯·韦伯太空望远镜发射升空的时候
So as we patiently wait for the Just Wait a Second Telescope to be launched,
我们可以期待一下它将带来的惊人科学发现
we can look forward to the incredible scientific discoveries it will make.
感谢Audible赞助本期视频
Thanks to Audible for making this video possible.
Audible拥有大量各种类别的有声书
Audible has an unmatched selection of audiobooks covering every topic imaginable.
我推荐的其中一本有声书是David Goggins写的《Can't Hurt Me》
One audiobook I'd recommend to anyone is “Can't Hurt Me” by David Goggins.
它讲述了David的传奇一生
It looks at David's incredible life story
并提供了克服恐惧与痛苦的办法 从而发挥自身最大潜力
and provides a path to get through pain and fear, in order to reach your full potential.
Audible应用免费 可以让你在任何设备任何时间听
The free Audible app allows you to listen to your audiobooks on any device at anytime.
如果你在考虑买个Audible的会员 那现在就是最好的时机
So if you're thinking about getting yourself an Audible membership, now is the best time to do it.
想要每月只要6.95元的首季度半价优惠吗
With this special offer, you can get 3 months of Audible for half price at just 6.95 a month!
赶快去下方链接或使用“primalspace”优惠代码吧
Start listening today by visiting audible.com/primalspace or text "primalspace" to 500 500.
感谢观看 我们下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video!